Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course and
this exercise number 48, we are asked to write a function to search for a specific value and then link
less.
So we have created the note class before, and these are the method that we have created in the previous
exercises.
Now let's go and create a new method called search public, and the return type is Boolean called search.
And it took the nod that you are going to search as sorry as the head of end of the linked list, and
it took the perimeter index that we are going to search for.
So we are going to find if this presented yes or not.
So we are going to search for that data for inside the nodes.
If it is presented or not.
OK, check whether the Value X is presented in the linked list or not that starts by their hat.
OK.
For that, I'll start by noncurrent equal to had.
While the current does not equal to null,
then if current DOT data equal equal to X again, it will return true.
So the data is found.
OK, now current.
Equal to Caryn.
Next, I'm moving here to curse.
OK, so here data.
So, OK.
This wide loop starts check if Karen does not equal turnout.
It starts by making if current data equal to the acts that we are going to search for, then return
true.
Otherwise increase current buy and move it to the next person to the next.
No.
And to check again, again and again until reaching current équatoriale, which is the cursor at the
end.
OK, otherwise if we break from this loop without finding that data, then return false.
OK.
It's very simple, but maybe ask in many exercises and many interviews.
Let's go up and let's go down to the main and search for it.
OK, here exercise.
By the way, you can get all these source codes and the link and the description and the resources folder
below.
Exercise number 48 Search for specific fat and link list.
So system that out.
Dot print.
Value of let me say, I'm searching for seven found
it yes or no.
So the injured list called the method search and pass the.
Had.
As Link at least had and the value that I am searching for is safe.
So we start with head.
We start with the head and start searching for that seven.
We have this count.
These are that nods for one, five and three.
They have that count that we have seen in the previous videos, but the value of seven found no, it
is false, so seven is not found.
OK, now let's check for numbers for.
Irish passport here and again, that's right.
Four, one, five and three five four is presented in the list, so if we come here, value of four
found, yes, it is true.
So it's very simple.
We have created a method that searches for a specific value inside that link, at least using that iteration.
Yeah, OK.
It's very simple.